Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Norman H. Strouse Papers, 1852-1990 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Business Writings and Speeches Series, 1935-1968 and undated, 10 Boxes
  - Bound Volumes
    - Vol. V, 1959
      - FDAF representatives comments (Box 13)
      - Executive committee of NOAB comments (Box 13)
      - What's New in the 60s? Advertising and Sales Club of Toronto (Box 13)
      - Should You Turn Your Mind Toward Advertising as a Career?, Advertising Career Conference (Box 13)
      - Comments to representatives of outdoor industry in meeting with NOAB (Box 13)
      - Owens-Illinois management comments (Box 13)
    - Vol. VI, 1960-1961
      - Divisional sales meetings, Scott Paper Company, comments, 1960 (Box 13)
      - Introduction to Marketing seminars, 1960 (Box 13)
      - Annual meeting of United Foundation of Metropolitan Detroit address, 1960 (Box 13)
      - Field seminar address, 1960 (Box 13)
      - Press conference comments, JWT Supermarket, 1960 (Box 13)
      - International Congress of Outdoor Advertising address, 1960 (Box 13)
      - Madison Avenue Is Many Places, AAAA Regional Council Meeting, 1960 (Box 13)
      - Meeting of vice presidents, notes, 1960 (Box 13)
      - JWT Christmas party remarks, 1960 (Box 13)
      - World Telegram & Sun guest column, 1961 (Box 13)
      - Meeting of JWT officers, comments, 1961 (Box 13)
      - Students Enrolled in a Field Study of Food Industries, Cornell University, 1961 (Box 13)
      - Modern Advertising, American Marvel or World Force? The Economic Club of Detroit, 1961 (Box 13)
      - JWT representatives, notes, 1961 (Box 13)
      - Response for Mr. Resor, Advertising Federation of American, Award for Distinguished Service, 1961 (Box 13)
      - What Is Profit?, Special request feature in Reader's Digest, 1961 (Box 13)
      - Color Television as an Advertising Medium article, Radio-TV Daily, 1961 (Box 13)
      - Sense of Responsibility, Guest column, New York Herald Tribune, 1961 (Box 13)
      - JWT field representatives comments, 1961 (Box 13)
      - Diversification Key to Detroit's Success Says JWT's Strouse, 1961 (Box 13)
      - Panel of Presidents, AAAA Western Region Convention, 1961 (Box 13)
      - Opening session of JWT's seminars, comments, 1961 (Box 13)
      - Introduction of Congressman John V. Lindsay, JWT luncheon, 1961 (Box 13)
      - Responsibility - Keynote of the Sixties, San Francisco Ad Club, 1961 (Box 13)
      - European Economic Community: Opportunity and Challenge to American Business, Annual Meeting of the Institute of Life Insurance, 1961 (Box 13)
      - Common Market, What It Offers, 1961 (Box 13)
    - Vol. VII, 1962-1963 (Box 14)
      - Advertising and the American Economy, article, Book of Knowledge, 1962 (Box 14)
      - Shoemaker Sans Shoes, Detroit Athletic Club Beavers, 1962 (Box 14)
      - FDA meeting comments, 1962 (Box 14)
      - Special Problems of Advertising Agency Management in the United States Today, AAAA Second International Meeting of Advertising Agency Leaders, 1962 (Box 14)
      - Growing One World of Advertising, Rochester Junion Chamber of Commerce, 1962 (Box 14)
      - Measuring the Value of Advertising in Our Society, American Marketing Association's 45th National Conference, 1962 (Box 14)
      - United Foundation of Metropolitan Detroit address, 1962 (Box 14)
      - JWT field service representatives, comments, 1963 (Box 14)
      - If You Believe in Advertising - Sell It!, Pittsburgh Advertising Club & Association of Industrial Advertisers, and Sales and Marketing Executives Club, 1963 (Box 14)
      - Officers of JWT, comments, 1963 (Box 14)
      - Talk at JWT Women's Group, 1963 (Box 14)
      - Kraft International Meeting at Burgenstock, talk, 1963 (Box 14)
      - FDAF dinner, Detroit Golf Club, 1963 (Box 14)
      - President's panel, AAAA East Central Region Convention, 1963 (Box 14)
    - Vol. VIII, 1964
      - Meeting of JWT representatives serving Ford dealers advertising funds, comments (Box 14)
      - Interview with Roy A. Newquist of Rand McNally & Co., notes (Box 14)
      - Agency Management Succession, AAAA Annual Meeting (Box 14)
      - Advertising - American Export or World Force?, Alpha Delta Sigma Initiation Program (Box 14)
      - Comments at meeting of JWT officers (Box 14)
      - Address to graduating class of Institute of Advanced Advertising Studios (Box 14)
      - Tribute to the Advertising Industry, response to the New York Advertising Agencies by the Mercantile Section, New York, Board of Trade, Inc. (Box 14)
      - Act of Faith, Marketing Science Institute (Box 14)
      - JWT personnel comments, Detroit Club dinner (Box 14)
      - JWT international managers meeting, closing remarks (Box 14)
      - Advertising and our Economy, the New School for Social Research (Box 14)
      - Growing Threat to Creativity, AAAA Western Region Conference (Box 14)
      - Personnel Projections Revisited, AAAA Annual Meeting Eastern Regional Convention (Box 14)
    - Vol. IX, 1965
      - Responsibility of Advertising in Today's Climate, Oscar Meyer Management Meeting (Box 14)
      - Response to award of Franklin Medal for Distinguished Service, Printing Industries of Metropolitan New York (Box 14)
      - Right to Be Heard, AAAA Annual meeting, Michigan Council, undated (Box 14)
      - Rising Threshold of Consumer Inattention, AAAA Rocky Mountain Council (Box 14)
      - Rising Threshold of Consumer Inattention, AAAA New England Region Boston Ad Club (Box 14)
      - As Far as I Can See, AAAA Annual Meeting (Box 14)
      - Advertising Relationship to Profit (Box 14)
      - Management Conference, Kraft Foods Division at Lucerne (Box 14)
      - Comments on retirement of O'Neill Ryan, FDAF (Box 14)
      - Bread Upon the Waters, Annual Convention of National Association fo Life Underwriters (Box 14)
      - Advertising article (Box 14)
      - Panel discussion, AAAA Eastern Conference luncheon (Box 14)
      - Hostages of Time, Annual Meeting of Association of National Advertisers (Box 14)
    - Vol. X, 1966-1968 (Box 15)
      - Advertising and the Enrichment of Life, Advertising Gold Medal Award acceptance speech, 1966 (Box 15)
      - Comments to participants in the JWT profit-sharing trust, 1966 (Box 15)
      - Today's Mouse Traps Must Go to Market, American Dairy Association, 1966 (Box 15)
      - Notes at dinner for FDAF field representatives and Detroit and New York Personnel, Detroit Club, 1966 (Box 15)
      - JWT annual party, notes, 1967 (Box 15)
      - Who Needs Advertising in an Affluent Society, National Automobile Dealers Association (NADA) Annual Meeting, 1967 (Box 15)
      - Role of Business in Protecting an Affluent Society, Chamber of Commerce of Wausau, Wisconsin, 1967 (Box 15)
      - How's Your Green Thumb Today?, AAAA 50th Anniversary Convention, 1967 (Box 15)
      - Internationalization of Advertising, Newsweek Global Report, 1967 (Box 15)
      - Is JWT on an Art Kick?, JWT Women's Luncheon Group, 1967 (Box 15)
      - Notes for JWT Director's Dinner, 1967 (Box 15)
      - Advertising, Prospect and Retrospect, Advertising Club of Los Angeles, 1968 (Box 15)
      - Advertising, the Most Public Kind of Responsibility, International Marketing Congress/American Marketing Association, 1968 (Box 15)
      - Memorandum to members of JWT, JWT, final JWT board meeting, 1968 (Box 15)
  - General Business Talks
    - Undated talks (Box 15)
    - 1955, Response to Testimonial, Adcraft Club of Detroit (Box 15)
    - 1956
      - What Is Your Newspaper's Target?, Newspaper Advertising Executives Association (Box 15)
      - Role of Advertising, Shell Management Course (Box 15)
      - Triptych for Advertising in the West, Advertising Association of the West (Box 15)
      - Velocity Is Your Challenge, Outdoor Advertising Association of America (Box 15)
      - Interurbia, the Implication of Management, Life Insurance Institute (Box 15)
    - 1957
      - Address to 27th Annual Business Conference, Harvard Business School Association (Box 15)
      - Address to Annual Meeting, Minneapolis Star & Tribune (Box 15)
      - Comments at Publishers Weekly, Publishers Adclub Advertising Awards luncheon (Box 15)
      - Magazine in a Changing America, Magazine Publishers Association (Box 15)
      - Nation on the Move (Box 15)
      - Newsletter excerpt (Box 16)
      - Seven Areas of Opportunity, Association of National Advertisers (Box 16)
    - 1958
      - Not All Beer and Skittles (Box 16)
      - Address to students, Colgate University Careers Conference (Box 16)
      - Address to L.P. Brown Alumni Rally, Olympia High School (Box 16)
      - Report of New Chairman of the Board, NOAB Executive Committee meeting (Box 16)
      - As Banking Goes to Market, Financial Public Relations Association Convention (Box 16)
      - Address to Rochester Advertisers (Box 16)
      - Address to Reader's Digest Sales Meeting (Box 16)
      - Some Publicity Results, National Wholesale Druggists Assocation (NWDA) meeting (Box 16)
      - Address to Utah Automobile Dealers Association (Box 16)
    - 1959
      - The 60s Are Less than a Year Away (Box 16)
      - Comments at Printer's Ink Gold Medal Award for 1958 to Roy Larsen (Box 16)
      - Comments at NOAB Executive Committee Meeting (Box 16)
      - William D. Laurie, Profile (Box 16)
      - What's New in the 60s?, address to Advertising Sales Club of Toronto (Box 16)
      - Should You Turn Your Mind Toward Advertising as a Career?, Advertising Career Club (Box 16)
      - Comments to Owens-Illinois Management (Box 16)
    - 1960
      - Comments at meeting with John Burns, RCA president (Box 16)
      - Address to Annual Meeting, United Foundation of Metropolitan Detroit (Box 16)
      - Address at International Outdoor Conference (Box 16)
      - Our Present Position and a Program for the Immediate Future (Box 17)
    - 1961
      - Comments at the meeting of JWT officers, New York Office (Box 17)
      - Main Issue: Sense of Responsiblity (Box 17)
      - Modern Advertising: American Marvel or World Force?, Economic Club of Detroit, (2 folders) (Box 17)
      - Responsibility...Keynote of the 60s, San Francisco Advertising Club, (3 folders) (Box 17)
      - What is Profit? reprint (Box 18)
      - Address to Annual Meeting of the Institute of Life Insurance (Box 18)
    - 1962
      - Address to Report Luncheon, United Foundation of Metropolitan Detroit (Box 18)
      - Advertising and the American Economy, Book of Knowledge Annual (Box 18)
      - Shoemaker Sans Shoes, Detroit Athletic Club Beavers (Box 18)
      - Ralph Breding Retirement Luncheon (Box 18)
      - Growing One World of Advertising, Rochester Junior Chamber of Commerce (Box 18)
      - Measuring the Value of Advertising in Our Society, American Marketing Associaion (AMA) Cincinnati (Box 18)
      - Text on Stanley Resor for JWT News (Box 18)
    - 1963
      - Comments on meeting of JWT field service representatives (Box 18)
      - Talk with JWT Women's Group, (2 folders) (Box 18)
      - If You Believe in Advertising - Sell It!, Pittsburgh Advertising Club (Box 18)
      - Talk at Kraft International Marketing Meeting (Box 18)
      - Talk at JWT Christmas Party (Box 18)
    - 1964
      - Advertising, American Export or World Force?, Alph Delta Sigma talk (Box 18)
      - Notes for announcement of election of Dan Seymour as President (Box 18)
      - Act of Faith, Address to marketing Science Institute (Box 18)
      - Comments to JWT personnel at Detroit Club dinner (Box 18)
      - Closing remarks JWT International Managers Meeting (Box 18)
      - Advertising and Our Economy (Box 18)
      - JWT Christmas party talk and newsletter message (Box 18)
    - 1965
      - Introduction to Dr. George H. Brown, Marketing Science Institute Meeting (Box 18)
      - Responsibility of Advertising in Today's Climate - Political or Economic, Oscar Mayer Management Meeting (Box 18)
      - Response in receipt of Franklin Medal for Distinguished Service (Box 19)
      - Rising Threshold of Consumer Inattention (Box 19)
      - Comment notes for New York office officers meeting (Box 19)
      - Bread Upon the Water, Annual Convention of National Association of Life Underwriters, (2 folders) (Box 19)
      - Hostages of Time, Association of National Advertisers (ANA) (Box 19)
      - Christmas Message, in JWT News (Box 19)
    - 1966
      - Advertising and the Enrichment of Life, Advertising Gold Medal Award speech, (3 folders) (Box 19)
      - Bruno Lucchesi premiere (Box 19)
      - Comments to Participants in the JWT Profit Sharing Trust (Box 19)
      - Introduction of Mr. Andrew Haskell, Marketing Science Institute (MSI) Conference (Box 19)
      - Night of the Owl, Theodore P. Jardine retirement dinner (Box 20)
      - Notes on presentation of the Sarnoff Crystal (Box 20)
      - Today's Mouse Traps Must Go to Market, American Dairy Association Annual Convention (Box 20)
    - 1967
      - Affluence and Advertising, condensed from speech at Wausau Chamber of Commerce (Box 20)
      - Announcing Strouse's retirement and Dan Seymour's appointment as CEO (Box 20)
      - Christmas Message, JWT News by Norman Strouse and Dan Seymour (Box 20)
      - Is JWT on an Art Kick? (Box 20)
      - JWT Christmas party (Box 20)
      - Response to Religion in American Life (RIAL) Tribute to JWT for 18 Years Service (Box 20)
      - Who Needs Advertising in an Affluent Society?, National Automobile Dealers Association (NADA) Annual Meeting (Box 20)
      - William D. Laurie, Jr., Ten Year Club (Box 20)
    - 1967-1968, Advertising: The Most Public Kind of Responsibility (Box 20)
    - 1968
      - Advertising: Prospect and Retrospect (Box 20)
      - Resignation speech to JWT Board of Directors (Box 20)
  - Detroit Office
    - Client presentations and speeches, 1948-1966 and undated, (2 folders) (Box 20)
    - Ford Dealer Advertising Funds (FDAF) (Box 21)
      - 1948, Outdoor-Its Burden of Proof, National Outdoor Advertising Bureau (NOAB) convention (Box 21)
      - 1949, Is Outdoor the Best Medium for Automobiles (Box 21)
      - 1950, Small Town Press as a Preservative in American Life, address before National Editorial Association (NEA) Convention (Box 21)
      - 1950 Dec., Part Creative Advertising Can Play in Marketing TBA Products, talk before the Oil Industry Tires, Batteries, Accessories (TBA) group (Box 21)
      - 1951, Necessity of Contacting Local Distributors and Dealers, NOAB Annual Convention (Box 21)
      - 1951 Dec., Discussion of Direct Mail Advertising, by Strouse and G.P. Richardson to FDAF (Box 21)
      - 1952, Address to Georgia Press Association (Box 21)
      - 1953, Address before Outdoor Advertising Association, National Convention (Box 21)
      - 1953, Address for the Annual Convention of International Electrotypers and Stereographers Association (Box 21)
      - 1953 Dec. 3, Talk to FDAF Committee Chairmen (Box 21)
      - 1954 June 9-11, Meeting Talk (Box 21)
      - 1955, Address to Wayne County Republican Women's Financial Committee (Box 21)
      - 1957 Sept. 30, Comments to FDAF Group (Box 21)
      - 1958 Aug. 7, Comments at 11th Annual Reunion, Ford Mechandising School (Box 21)
      - 1958 Sept. 5, Comments to FDAF Group (Box 21)
      - 1966, Aug., Comments to FDAF meeting (Box 21)
      - 1962, Marketing strategy (Box 21)
      - 1963, Moving Minds to Ford (Box 21)
      - 1963 Aug. 19, Comments at FDAF Dinner (Box 21)
      - 1965 Aug., Comments at dinner for FDAF field members on retirement of O'Neill Ryan (Box 21)
  - San Francisco Office
    - Undated, Outdoor advertising and media speeches (Box 21)
    - 1935, How to Measure Your Market (Box 21)
    - 1937, April 12, Strengthening the Newspaper Presentation (Box 21)
    - 1939, Jan 9, Institute of Life Insurance (Box 21)
    - 1940, Apr. 1, The Last Town Hall - Your Newspaper, Oakland Advertising Club (Box 21)
    - 1940 October, No News is Bad News (Box 21)
- Book Collecting, Library and Printing Interests Series, 1950-1989 and undated
  Includes speeches, articles, publications, clippings, agendas, correspondence, photographs and a transcript that predominantly relate to Strouse's book collecting, the history of printing and fine printing. Contains documents relating to aspects of Norman H. Strouse's hand press, the Silverado Press, and his bibliophilic interests, especially the work of Robert Louis Stevenson. Norman and Charlotte Strouse were instrumental in the establishment of the Silverado Museum which focuses on Robert Louis Stevenson. Some information about this museum is scattered in the correspondence files of General office and personal series. Reproductions from Norman and Charlotte Strouse's collection of manuscripts and rare books are included in the Christmas Greeting category. The transcript is of the ABC television show Scope entitled Ad Lib that features Norman and Charlotte Strouse. Arranged alphabetically. Divided into four subseries: Writings and addresses by Norman H. Strouse, Silverado Press, Christmas greetings and Miscellaneous. Writings and Addresses by Norman H. Strouse consist of items primarily from the years 1959-1968, arranged alphabeticaly by title. Silverado Press consists of pamphlets privately printed by Norman H. Strouse; works by or about Robert Louis Stevenson; a pamphlet on the Silverado Museum; and artwork for the press's bookplate, arranged alphabetically. Christmas Greetings include privately printed cards and pamphlets with reproductions from the collection of Norman and Charlotte Strouse, along with reprints of essays by Norman Strouse and others. Some include descriptions of the reproductions by the Strouses and others. Several may have been issued by the Silverado Museum. Arranged chronologically. Miscellaneous contains correspondence, articles, programs, photographs and clippings related to and about Strouse's interest in books and libraries. A number of the folders are concerned with National Library Week; Norman Strouse was a member of its steering committee from 1958 to 1963. Arranged alphabetically.
  - Writings and Addresses by Norman H. Strouse
    - ABC Scope program, 1965, (2 folders) (Box 22)
    - Address at the Bookseller's League of New York, 1958 (Box 22)
    - Address to University of California Santa Cruz affiliates, 1969 (Box 22)
    - Chairman's report, National Book Committee annual meeting, 1963-1964, (2 folders) (Box 22)
    - Cobden Sanderson: Binder, Printer, Mystic, Guild of Book Workers, 1964 (Box 22)
    - Colgate Library and National Library Week, Colgate University Library, 1959 (Box 22)
    - Comments at Denver Library reception, 1965 (Box 22)
    - Contemptible Horse, by John Ruskin, Introductory Essay by Norman H. Strouse, 1962 (Box 22)
    - How to Build a Poor Man's Morgan Library, 1959 (2 copies) (Box 22)
    - Ladies In My Library: Books and Letters from the Collection of Norman H. Strouse, 1968 (2 copies) (Box 23)
    - Ladies in my Library, Manuscript Society talk, 1966 (Box 23)
    - Lengthened Shadow, an Address by Norman H. Strouse at the Grolier Club, 1960 (Box 23)
    - McKinley Junior High School talk, 1968 (Box 23)
    - National Library Week, speech before Magazine Promotion Group, 1962 (Box 23)
    - New Star in Temple, Charles Trumball Hayden Library dedication, 1966 (Box 23)
    - Passionate Pirate, Thomas Bird Mosher, Society of Printers, 1963 (Box 23)
    - Passionate Pirate, 1964 (Box 23)
    - Pleasures of Packing a Library (reprint), 1968 (Box 23)
    - Pleasures of Paper Are Infinite, 1963 (Box 23)
    - Silverado Episode, 1966 (2 copies) (Box 23)
  - Silverado Press
    - Letter from T.J. Cobden-Sanderson "To my dear Rbt.", 20 November 1914, 1950; photograph of Emery Walker and T.J. Cobden-Sanderson, undated (Box 23)
    - Silverado Museum, a Twenty Year Retrospective, 1989 (Box 23)
    - Silverado Press bookplate sketch, undated (Box 23)
    - Robert Louis Stevenson, 1971 and undated
      - The Silverado Squatters by Robert Louis Stevenson, undated (Box 23)
      - The Silverado Squatters: Robert Louis Stevenson by Lawrence Clark Powell (reprint), 1971 (Box 23)
    - A Spirited Enterprise, by Marshall E. Dimock, 1961 (2 copies) (Box 23)
  - Christmas Greetings
    - Miscellaneous, 1961-1986 and undated (Box 24)
  - Miscellaneous Materials
    - Case of the Private Press, Type Talks, 1961 (Box 24)
    - Christmas and Artistic Expression Led to Silverado Press Founding, Inland Printer, 1956 (Box 24)
    - Correspondence, 1958-1986 (Box 24)
    - Gala Book Week at the Grolier Club, visit to Strouse's library, 1964 (Box 24)
    - Home Hobbyists Delight in Toiling Over a Hot Press, New York Times, 1963 (Box 24)
    - Manuscript Society, 15th annual meeting, 1962 (Box 24)
    - National Library Week, 1958-1959
      - 1958 (Box 24)
      - 1959 planning, 1958-1959 (Box 24)
      - Strouse elected chairman, 1961 (Box 24)
    - New York Public Library Fund, Strouse named chairman, 1965 (Box 24)
    - Norman H. Strouse: a Profile in Books, Christian Science Monitor, 1960 (Box 24)
    - Norman H. Strouse: Curiosity Is a Tool, Printer's Ink, ca. 1954-1955 (Box 24)
- Personal Materials Series, 1852-1990 and undated, 6 Boxes
  Includes material relating to Strouse's private life. Some materials were collected for a book on Strousse's life, also included in the series, and presented to him on the occasion of his retirement from JWT. The series consists of four categories: Clippings, Correspondence, Memorabilia and Photographs. See also Oversize Materials. Arranged alphabetically.
  - Clippings, 1852-1924 (Box 24)
  - Correspondence, 1941-1990
    - General, 1968-1969 (Box 24)
    - Army records, 1941-1967, (3 folders) (Box 24)
    - Bob Haldeman, 1956-1978 (Box 25)
    - Helen Hickey, 1981-1990 (Box 25)
    - Friends from JWT days, 1965-1990 (Box 25)
    - Lord Thomson luncheon, 1967 (Box 25)
    - Personal acknowledgements, 1951-1968 and undated, (3 folders) (Box 25)
    - Retirement letters, 1968, (3 folders) (Box 25)
    - Stock issues, JWT, 1950-1973 (Box 25)
    - Strouse's retirement book background materials and correspondence, 1965-1970 (Box 26)
    - Strouse's 60th birthday, 1966 (Box 26)
    - Strouse's 70th birthday, 1976 (Box 26)
  - Memorabilia, 1934-1986
    - AAAA
      - Chairman of the board commemorative metal box, 1964-1965 (Box 26)
      - Meeting medal, 1962 (Box 26)
    - American Federation of Advertisers, American Association of the West, Printer's Ink Network Distinguished Service Award medal with stand, 1966 (Box 26)
    - Bound certificate to accompany New York Public Library anniversary medal, 1961 (Box 27)
    - Bound citation from Board of Trustees, Temple University, 1965 (Box 27)
    - Bound citation to Norman Strouse from National Outdoor Advertising Bureau on illuminated vellum, 1961 (Box 27)
    - Cartoon of Norman Strouse as an artist, undated (Box 27)
    - Cartoon showing people coming to see Norman Strouse, undated (Box 27)
    - Columbia University, School of Engineering and Applied Science Centennial, 1964 (Box 27)
    - First National Bank 150th birthday medal, 1962 (Box 27)
    - Forbes 50 Foremost Business Leaders, 1957
      - Correspondence and clippings (Box 27)
      - Keychain (Box 27)
      - Medal (Box 27)
    - Framed certificate from Alpha Delta Sigma National Advertising Fraternity for Men, 1964 (Box 27)
    - Framed letter from Yousuf Karsh, 1984 (Box 27)
    - Franklin Award for Distinguished Service, medal and photographs, 1965 (Box 28)
    - Jardine memorabilia, 1961-1983 (Box 28)
    - JWT 125th anniversary lapel pin and letter, 1989 (Box 28)
    - JWT centennial paperweight, 1964 (Box 28)
    - JWT centennial medal from JWT Italy, 1964 (Box 28)
    - New York Public Library medal, 1961 (Box 28)